

### **Martin Maca**

Junior Software Developer

### **Contact details**

- -+420 601 531 920
- maca.martin@atlas.cz
- remote, willing to relocate

#### Core Skills

- Programming
- CAD design
- Design of special-purpose machines
- Project planing
- Scheaduling
- Client presentations
- Networking

# **Professional Profile**

I have a combined 8 years of experience in different fields of industrial automation. From machine design, programming machine logic, designing and programming HMI systems, to servicing industrial robots and machines. I have good proficiency in a range of CAD software, high level of proficiency in programming Epson industrial robots, I also have experience programming PLCs in Structured Text, a standardized IEC 61131-3 language. I am very passionate about and have a varying degree of experience with standard software development. Programming languages in which I have used to in the past include C+++, Java, HTML and Processing.

## **Career Summary**

#### Feb 2023 - Present Internac Solutions, s.r.o., Kuřim Czech Republic

Research and Development Specialist

Outline

Internac Solutions is a non-profit organization focused on helping SMEs within our region with automation and digitalization. My primary role in the company is to help identify processes suitable for automation, draft a practical and economical solution, test the proposed solution in our testbed, and communicate my analysis with customers.

### 2017 - 2022 Opticontrol s.r.o., Lelekovice Czech Republic

Programmer and design Engineer

Outline

Opticontrol is a company focused on industrial automation. Main area of focus is single machine design and manufacturing, mainly for the automotive industry. I was tasked with designing and programming of the single purpose machines, and I got to experience the complete lifecycle of each machine.

### 2016 - 2017 Balak Stroje Tišnov s.r.o., Tišnov

Machine technician

Outline

Small family company focused on designing and building machining tools. Their main customers are companies in the automotive industry.

### Jan 2015 - Dec 2015 Global Languages, Pereira, Colombia

Engligh teacher

Outline

Teaching English to kids and adults as part of a AIESEC student intership program.

## **Education**

- Bachelor degree | Brno University of Technology | 2011 2014
- High School Graduate | Grammar School Tišnov | 2006 2010
- Student Exchange Program | Bountiful High School, Utah, USA | Jan 2008 Jul 2008

# **Certificates**

- Universal Robots Advanced training | 2023
- Epson Robots Maintenance | 2019
- National Welding Certificate MAG 135 1.1 | 2016